Smith Edwards Architects Photograph Collection
Hartford History Center, Hartford Public Library
Smith Edwards Architects Photograph Collection
1979-1992
Hartford History Center, Hartford Public Library Hartford, Connecticut
Smith Edwards Architects
3.5 linear feet
Photographs of historic buildings in Hartford renovated by Smith Edwards Architects between the 1970s and 1990s.
Historical Note
Smith Edwards Architects was formed by Tyler Smith and Jared Edwards in 1977. Tyler Smith was one of the founders of the Hartford Architecture Conservancy and the firm was known for its preservation work in Hartford, including the rehabilitation of many historic buildings. The firm became Smith Edwards McCoy Architects in 2012 when Kent McCoy was made a partner. In 2017, the firm merged with Quisenberry Arcari Architects of Farmington and continued operating in Farmington under that name.
Scope and Content
The collection includes 35mm slides, photographic prints, contact sheets, and negatives documenting the renovation of historic Hartford buildings by Smith Edwards Architects. The firm’s work on houses and commercial buildings on Congress Street between 1979 and 1985 is especially well represented. Martin-Belair, a partnership between William B. Martin and Jean R. Belair, Jr., was also involved with this project. Other projects by Smith Edwards include Billings Forge, the Day-Taylor House on Wethersfield Avenue, renovations to the Old State House in 1992, and the South Green Redevelopment Project. Developers Howard Nannen and Madelyn Colon collaborated with Smith Edwards on some of these projects. The collection was organized by the architectural firm prior to its donation to the Hartford History Center and the original order of the folders are preserved. In addition to the photographic material, the folders include paperwork from the photographer Roger Dollarhide who took most of the photographs.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series, topically and chronologically.
Access Restrictions
The records are stored in a restricted area and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Accruals
The collection is closed. Additional accruals are not expected.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Belair, Jean R., Jr.; Colon, Madelyn; Dollarhide, Roger; Edwards, Jared; Martin, William B.; Nannen, Howard; Smith, Tyler
Corporate Names
Arrow-Hart & Hegeman; Billings Forge; Martin Belair; Hartford Architecture Conservancy; Old State House (Hartford, Conn.); Royal Typewriter Company; Smith Edwards Architects
Subjects
Apartment houses; Architectural firms; Commercial buildings; Construction; Demolition; Dwellings; Historic preservation; Restaurants; Urban renewal
Geographic names
Congress Street (Hartford, Conn.); Hartford (Conn.)
Genre Terms
Photographs
Contents:
- Photographs
  - Billings Forge Redevelopment Project, 140 Russ Street, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 15, 17, 19 Charter Oak Place, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Congress Street, completed apartments, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Congress Street, elevations, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Congress Street, problem areas, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Congress Street, south building progress, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Congress Street, copies of old photographs, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Congress Street, Morris and Alden Street, porches and elevations, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Congress Street, porches and elevations, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Congress Street, progress and elevations, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Congress Street, redevelopment project, 1979-1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Congress Street, redevelopment project, 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Congress Street, 65 Wethersfield Avenue, interior, exterior views, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Day-Taylor House (Hartford Architecture Conservancy), Wethersfield Avenue, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Day-Taylor House (Hartford Architecture Conservancy), Wethersfield Avenue, Frog Hollow, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Day-Taylor House (Hartford Architecture Conservancy), Wethersfield Avenue, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Day-Taylor House (Hartford Architecture Conservancy), Wethersfield Avenue, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Day-Taylor House (Hartford Architecture Conservancy), Wethersfield Avenue, open house, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Martin Belair Developers, Atlantic Screwworks Building, Congress Street, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Martin Belair Developers, Atlantic Screwworks Building, Congress Street, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Martin Belair Developers, Church Street building, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Martin Belair Developers, Congress Street, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Congress Street, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Congress Street, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Congress Street, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Congress Street, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 17-19 Congress Street, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 26 Congress Street, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 27 Congress Street, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 26, 27 Congress Street, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 34 Congress Street, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 38 Congress Street, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 37-39 Congress Street, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 42-44 Congress Street, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 64-66 Congress Street, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Martin Belair Developers, Congress Street update, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Martin Belair Developers, Imlay Street, rear views, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Martin Belair Developers, Congress Street Project doorways, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Martin Belair Developers, HABS documentation of Congress Street redevelopment houses, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Dean Street, Alden Street, 1979-1980? (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Martin Belair Developers, Franklin Avenue and Brown Street doorway, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 22-24 Maple Avenue, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 54-58 Maple Avenue, 26 Congress debris, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 54-58 Maple Avenue, 26 Congress Street debris, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 12-20 Morris Street, demolition, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 64-66 Morris Street, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 68-70 Morris Street, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 49-51 Morris Street, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Martin Belair Developers, 65 Wethersfield Avenue, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Smith Edwards Architecture, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Atheneum roof, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Arrow-Hart complex, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Arrow-Hart complex, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Billings Forge, including copies of floor plans, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Billings Forge, open house, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Billings Forge, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Billings Forge, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, 44-52 Buckingham Street, 1979-1981 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, 450 Capitol Avenue, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, 470 Capitol Avenue, 1981-1983 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Congress Street, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Congress Street, streetscapes, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Connecticut State Capitol, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Day-Taylor House, third floor, Wethersfield Avenue, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Day-Taylor House, Wethersfield Avenue, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Day-Taylor House, Wethersfield Avenue, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, 79 Elm Street, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Hartford College for Women, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Hartford Public Library, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Heritage Group, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Hotel Capitol, Main Street, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Labor Temple, Park Street, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, 195 Retreat Avenue, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Madelyn Colon Real Estate office, Park Street, 199-? (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, McKone Building, Main Street, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, 64-66 Morris Street, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, 68-70 Morris Street, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Howard Nannen, 15 Charter Oak Place, houses and carriage house, 1980? (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Howard Nannen, 19 Charter Oak Place, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Old State House, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Peck House, Main Street near South green, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Phoenix Building; 470 Capitol Avenue; Morgan Wing, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Pratt Street, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, 195 Retreat Avenue, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Royal Typewriter aerials, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Royal Typewriter Building, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, slide copies, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Townley Street Apartments, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Townley Street Apartments, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Smith Edwards Architects, Tyler Smith residence interiors, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - 74 Union Place, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - William Martin, Congress Street model, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - William Martin, HUD, South Green redevelopment buildings, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous contact sheets, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous slides, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous negatives and receipts, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 6)